Guide to the Cecile Pineda Papers, 1959 - 1998
Department of Special Collections
- Series 2. Manuscripts
  - Subseries 2. Frieze
    - FRIEZE: art work for end papers, Creator's Id No. 6.14 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - FRIEZE: readers' comments, Creator's Id No. 6.15 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - FRIEZE: reviews, Creator's Id No. 6.16 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - FRIEZE: unrevised, unpublished proof, Creator's Id No. 6.17 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - FRIEZE: first edition, hard cover, signed, Creator's Id No. 6.18 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - FRIEZE: second edition, soft cover, signed, Creator's Id No. 6.19 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 3. Love Queen of the Amazon
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: research, Creator's Id No. 9.01 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: original composition, Creator's Id No. 9.02 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: synopses, plotting, Creator's Id No. 9.03 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: readers' comments, Creator's Id No. 9.04 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: Chapter 1, draft 1, 1990 Apr., Creator's Id No. 9.05 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: first draft [1 of 4], Creator's Id No. 9.06 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: first draft [2 of 4], Creator's Id No. 9.06 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: first draft [3 of 4], Creator's Id No. 9.06 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: first draft [4 of 4], Creator's Id No. 9.06 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: draft 2, Lichtner comments [1 of 3]1990 Mar. 13, Creator's Id No. 9.07 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: draft 2, Lichtner comments [2 of 3]1990 Mar. 13, Creator's Id No. 9.07 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: draft 2, Lichtner comments [3 of 3]1990 Mar. 13, Creator's Id No. 9.07 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: draft 2, readers' comments, Creator's Id No. 9.08 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: early draft [1 of 2], Creator's Id No. 9.09 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: early draft [2 of 2], Creator's Id No. 9.09 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: early draft rewrites [1 of 3], Creator's Id No. 9.1 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: early draft rewrites [2 of 3], Creator's Id No. 9.1 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: early draft rewrites [3 of 3], Creator's Id No. 9.1 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: rewrites1991 July, Creator's Id No. 9.11 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: early draft: pp. 1-348 [1 of 3], Creator's Id No. 9.12 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: early draft: pp. 1-348 [2 of 3], Creator's Id No. 9.12 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: early draft: pp. 1-348 [3 of 3], Creator's Id No. 9.12 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: Sydney Carson's comments, Chapters 11, 12, 13, Creator's Id No. 9.13 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: rough draft, marine invasion1991, Creator's Id No. 9.14 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: polished draft, marine invasion1991, Creator's Id No. 9.15 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: Marine invasion: pp. 197-313, rejected1991, Creator's Id No. 9.16 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: Fetus president breakthrough, cast as dream, Creator's Id No. 9.17 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: intermediate draft, rejected material, Creator's Id No. 9.18 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: intermediate draft, Chapters 1-8 [1 of 2], Creator's Id No. 9.19 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: intermediate draft, Chapters 1-8 [2 of 2], Creator's Id No. 9.19 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: intermediate draft, rejected material [1 of 3], 1990 Oct., Creator's Id No. 9.2 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: intermediate draft, rejected material [2 of 3], 1990 Oct., Creator's Id No. 9.2 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: intermediate draft, rejected material [3 of 3], 1990 Oct., Creator's Id No. 9.2 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: intermediate draft [1 of 4]1990, Creator's Id No. 9.21 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: intermediate draft [2 of 4]1990, Creator's Id No. 9.21 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: intermediate draft [3 of 4]1990, Creator's Id No. 9.21 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: intermediate draft [4 of 4]1990, Creator's Id No. 9.21 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: penultimate draft, Chapters 1-8 [1 of 2]1990 Nov., Creator's Id No. 9.22 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: penultimate draft, Chapters 1-8 [2 of 2]1990 Nov., Creator's Id No. 9.22 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: penultimate draft, Chapters 9-111990 Nov., Creator's Id No. 9.23 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: closing chapter1992, Creator's Id No. 9.24 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: changes, 1992 Mar., Creator's Id No. 9.25 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: final draft, copyedited, [1 of 4]1992, Creator's Id No. 9.26 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: final draft, copyedited, [2 of 4]1992, Creator's Id No. 9.26 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: final draft, copyedited, [3 of 4]1992, Creator's Id No. 9.26 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: final draft, copyedited, [4 of 4]1992, Creator's Id No. 9.26 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: copyedited mss, [1 of 4]1992 July 22, Creator's Id No. 10.01 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: copyedited mss, [2 of 4]1992 July 22, Creator's Id No. 10.01 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: copyedited mss, [3 of 4]1992 July 22, Creator's Id No. 10.01 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: copyedited mss, [4 of 4]1992 July 22, Creator's Id No. 10.01 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: page proof [1 of 2], Creator's Id No. 10.02 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: page proof [1 of 2], Creator's Id No. 10.02 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: corrected page proof [1 of 2], Creator's Id No. 10.03 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: corrected page proof [2 of 2], Creator's Id No. 10.03 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: IRS certification, Creator's Id No. 10.04 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: Little, Brown, & Co. contract; correspondence; publicity, Creator's Id No. 10.05 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: Little, Brown, & Co. contract; correspondence, Calamaro Agency, Creator's Id No. 10.06 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: Little, Brown, & Co. remainders, Creator's Id No. 10.07 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: Bertelsmann-Verlag, German edition, Creator's Id No. 10.08 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: Uitgeverij-Arena, Dutch edition, Creator's Id No. 10.09 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: Hamish Hamilton/Penguin, UK edition, Creator's Id No. 10.1 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: reviews, Creator's Id No. 10.11 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: Little Brown & Co.: uncorrected advance proof, Creator's Id No. 10.12 (Box 31)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: Little Brown & Co.: hard cover first edition, Creator's Id No. 10.13 (Box 31)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: Little Brown & Co.: paperback second edition, Creator's Id No. 10.14 (Box 31)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: Little Brown & Co.: Hamish Hamilton, First edition, UK, Creator's Id No. 10.15 (Box 31)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: Little Brown & Co.: Penguin, Second edition, UK, Creator's Id No. 10.16 (Box 31)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: advance corrected proof, German edition, Creator's Id No. 10.17 (Box 31)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: Bertelsmann hard cover, first German edition, Creator's Id No. 10.18 (Box 31)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: Bertelsmann/Goldmman, second German edition, Creator's Id No. 10.19 (Box 31)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: Bertelsmann/Goldmman, third German edition, Creator's Id No. 10.2 (Box 31)
    - LOVE QUEEN OF THE AMAZON: Uitgeverij-Arena hard cover, first Dutch edition, Creator's Id No. 10.21 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 4. Fishlight
    - FISHLIGHT: revision, 1998 June 28 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - FISHLIGHT: revision, 1998 June 27 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - FISHLIGHT: revised ms1998 Mar. 15, Creator's Id No. 11.01 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - FISHLIGHT: draft, 1998 Mar., Creator's Id No. 11.02 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - FISHLIGHT: revision, 1998 Feb., Creator's Id No. 11.03 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - FISHLIGHT: draft, 1996 Sept., Creator's Id No. 11.04 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - FISHLIGHT: revision, 1996 Aug. 13, Creator's Id No. 11.05 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - FISHLIGHT: draft, 1996 Aug., Creator's Id No. 11.06 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - FISHLIGHT: draft, 1996 early Aug., Creator's Id No. 11.07 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - FISHLIGHT: draft, 1996 Nov., Creator's Id No. 11.08 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - FISHLIGHT: draft, 1995 Nov., Creator's Id No. 11.08 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - FISHLIGHT: draft, 1995 Aug., Creator's Id No. 11.09 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - FISHLIGHT: draft, [1 of 2]1994 Jan., Creator's Id No. 11.1 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - FISHLIGHT: draft, [2 of 2]1994, Creator's Id No. 11.1 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - FISHLIGHT: bound draft,1994 Jan., Creator's Id No. 11.11 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - FISHLIGHT: Sydney Carson's comments, 1994 Jan., Creator's Id No. 11.12 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - FISHLIGHT: revision of plot scheme, Creator's Id No. 11.13 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - FISHLIGHT: preliminary draft with revision & notes, Creator's Id No. 11.14 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - FISHLIGHT: original material [1 of 2], Creator's Id No. 11.15 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - FISHLIGHT: original material [2 of 2], Creator's Id No. 11.15 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - FISHLIGHT: copy with David Mark's notes, 1993, Creator's Id No. 11.16 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - FISHLIGHT: draft, 1993 Dec., Creator's Id No. 11.17 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - FISHLIGHT: draft, 1993 Dec. 20, Creator's Id No. 11.18 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - FISHLIGHT: draft, 1993 Oct., Creator's Id No. 11.19 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - FISHLIGHT: copy with student comments, Creator's Id No. 11.2 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - FISHLIGHT: draft, 1993 Oct., Creator's Id No. 11.21 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - FISHLIGHT: copy with Sydney Carson's notes, 1993 Oct. 3, Creator's Id No. 11.22 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - FISHLIGHT: copy with David Mark's notes, 1993 Aug., Creator's Id No. 11.23 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - FISHLIGHT: draft, 1993 June, Creator's Id No. 11.24 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - FISHLIGHT: draft,1993 Apr. 23, Creator's Id No. 11.25 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - FISHLIGHT: draft, [1 of 2]1992 Dec., Creator's Id No. 11.26 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - FISHLIGHT: draft, [2 of 2]1992 Dec., Creator's Id No. 11.26 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - FISHLIGHT: early draft, Creator's Id No. 11.27 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - FISHLIGHT: early material, Creator's Id No. 11.28 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 5. Redoubt
    - REDOUBT: mysterious parents (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - REDOUBT: old reports, lines not used (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - REDOUBT: research, Creator's Id No. 12.01 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - REDOUBT: first draft, 1987 Mar. - Sept., Creator's Id No. 12.02 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - REDOUBT: original material, 1987 Aug. 22, Creator's Id No. 12.03 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - REDOUBT: rough draft, [1 of 2]1988, Creator's Id No. 12.04 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - REDOUBT: rough draft, [2 of 2]1988, Creator's Id No. 12.04 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - REDOUBT: revision, 1995, Creator's Id No. 12.05 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - REDOUBT: revision, 1996 Jan. 18, Creator's Id No. 12.06 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - REDOUBT: draft, 1997 Mar., Creator's Id No. 12.07 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - REDOUBT: draft, 1997 Mar., Creator's Id No. 12.08; duplicate (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - REDOUBT: draft,1997 Aug., Creator's Id No. 12.09 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - REDOUBT: draft,1997 Aug., Creator's Id No. 12.1 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - REDOUBT: rewrites and edits, 1997 Aug., Creator's Id No. 12.11 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - REDOUBT: revision, [1 of 2]1997 Aug., Creator's Id No. 12.12 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - REDOUBT: revision, [2 of 2]1997 Aug., Creator's Id No. 12.12 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - REDOUBT: final draft, 1997 Nov., Creator's Id No. 12.13 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - REDOUBT: final draft, 1997 Nov., Creator's Id No. 12.14 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - REDOUBT: mss, 1998 Sept., Creator's Id No. 12.15 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - REDOUBT: reader's comments, Creator's Id No. 12.16 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - REDOUBT: revision, 1998 June, Creator's Id No. 12.17 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 6. Bardo
    - BARDO: mss, 1999 June 14, Creator's Id No. 13.01 (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - BARDO: draft, 1999 Mar. 21, Creator's Id No. 13.02 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - BARDO: revisions, 1999 Mar., Creator's Id No. 13.03 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - BARDO: Part 3: Hotel -- Part 4: Dream -- Part 5: Ward, 1999 Feb. 18, Creator's Id No. 13.04 (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - BARDO1999 Feb. 10, Creator's Id No. 13.05 (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - BARDO1999 Feb. 2, Creator's Id No. 13.06 (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - BARDO: part III, 1999 Jan. 29-30, Creator's Id No. 13.07 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - BARDO: Third person, 1998 Nov. 10, Creator's Id No. 13.08 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - BARDO: First person, 1998 Sept., Creator's Id No. 13.09 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - BARDO: First person, 1998 Aug., Creator's Id No. 13.1 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - BARDO: American idiom, 1996 July 21-31, Creator's Id No. 13.11 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - BARDO: Yankee idiom, 1996 July 31, Creator's Id No. 13.11 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - BARDO: work to break out, Creator's Id No. 13.12 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - BARDO: Part II: Walkabout, 1996 July 6, Creator's Id No. 13.13 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - BARDO: with readers' comments, 1996 Aug. 7, Creator's Id No. 13.14 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - BARDO: revision, 1996 July, Creator's Id No. 13.15 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - BARDO: revision, 1996 June 6, Creator's Id No. 13.16 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - BARDO: Part I: The Call, 1993 May, Creator's Id No. 13.17 (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - BARDO: Exit material, 1993, Creator's Id No. 13.18 (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - BARDO: rough draft: Sydney Carson's comments, 1992 July 10, Creator's Id No. 13.19 (Box 39, Folder 14)
    - BARDO: rough draft: David Mark's comments1992, Creator's Id No. 13.2 (Box 39, Folder 15)
    - BARDO: draft IV, [1 of 2]1992 Feb. 14, Creator's Id No. 13.21 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - BARDO: draft IV, [2 of 2]1992 Feb. 14, Creator's Id No. 13.21 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - BARDO: Lesh-Nyham version, Creator's Id No. 13.22 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - BARDO: Norah Holmgren's comments, 1989 Dec., Creator's Id No. 13.23 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - BARDO: draft, baby in arms version1989, Creator's Id No. 13.24 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - BARDO: babe in arms, draft III, revised, Creator's Id No. 13.25; In blue folder (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - BARDO: (working title: Room) drafts 2 & 3 [1 of 2]1989 Oct. 16-27, Creator's Id No. 13.26 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - BARDO: (working title: Room) drafts 2 & 3 [2 of 2]1989 Oct. 16-27, Creator's Id No. 13.26 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - BARDO: reader's comments: David Marks, M. Gonzalez, 1989 June 21, Creator's Id No. 13.27 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - BARDO: draft II, including Letters & Room, 1989, Creator's Id No. 13.28 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - BARDO: draft I revisions, Creator's Id No. 13.29 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - BARDO: first draft, Creator's Id No. 13.3 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - BARDO: Letter: text, original and duplicate, Creator's Id No. 13.31 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - BARDO: Hotel section, 1989, Creator's Id No. 13.32 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - BARDO: (working title: Room) draft II, 1989 May 4, Creator's Id No. 13.33 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - BARDO: Room, 1989 May 4, Creator's Id No. 13.34 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - BARDO1989 Feb. 6, Creator's Id No. 13.35 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - BARDO: Letters and Room I 1989, Creator's Id No. 13.36 (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - BARDO: transitional material, Creator's Id No. 13.37 (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - BARDO: draft, 1986, Creator's Id No. 13.38 (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - BARDO: original draft, revised, Creator's Id No. 13.39 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - LETTERS: original draft, Creator's Id No. 13.4 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - THE ROOM: original short story, Creator's Id No. 13.41 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - 20th Century Research, Creator's Id No. 13.42 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Breyten Breytenbach: confessions of an albino terrorist, Creator's Id No. 13.43 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Chernobyl research, Creator's Id No. 13.44 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - BARDO: Chicano / a literary contents, 1999 June 21, Creator's Id No. 13.45 (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - BARDO: corrections, 1999 Mar.; 1999 June, Creator's Id No. 13.45 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - BARDO: draft corrections, 1999 Mar., Creator's Id No. 13.46 (Box 42, Folder 8)
- Series 3. Ruth Brinker biography project files
  - Shorthand notebook, Creator's Id No. 15.01 (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Shorthand notebook, interview transcripts, 1994 May 24 - 1994 Sept. 15, Creator's Id No. 15.02 (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Research material and outline, Creator's Id No. 15.03 (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Proposal: outline & preface, Creator's Id No. 15.04 (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Interviews 1 - 5, Creator's Id No. 15.05 (Box 42, Folder 12)
- Series 4. Journals
  Journals are restricted until review by creator is completed.
  - Diary of a Pregnant Housewife1959 Apr. 14, Creator's Id No. 1 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Job; Attica; Mother1970 -1972, Creator's Id No. 2 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Trial; divorce1974 Sept. - 1975 July, Creator's Id No. 3 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Polish Theater trip1977, Creator's Id No. 4 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Bruno (breakthrough to fiction)1979 Oct. 22 - 1987 May 5, Creator's Id No. 5 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Fugue episode (breakthrough to fiction)1980 Oct. 10, Creator's Id No. 6 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Face1980 Dec. 6 - 1981 Aug. 5, Creator's Id No. 7 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Face; Runes1980 Apr. 4 - 1983 Oct. 23, Creator's Id No. 8 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Trip to Spain & Morocco1981 Aug. 1 - 1982 Sept. 3, Creator's Id No. 9 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Face; Silo Solo; Trip to Mexico1981 Aug. 7 - 1982 Jan. 27, Creator's Id No. 10 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Face; research1982 Jan. 13 - 1982 July 27, Creator's Id No. 11; Photocopy; restricted materials pulled (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Low Country; Face; Mr. Al, Ms. Cat1983 Jan. 5 - 1983 Dec. 5, Creator's Id No. 12; Photocopy; restricted materials pulled (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Frieze1983 Dec. 5 - 1985 May 8, Creator's Id No. 13; Photocopy; restricted materials pulled (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Frieze1984 Jan. 8 - 1984 Mar. 12, Creator's Id No. 14; Photocopy; restricted materials pulled (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Frieze1984 June 1 - 1985 May, Creator's Id No. 15 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - George Shar; Passage1985 Apr. 17 - 1985 Oct., Creator's Id No. 16; Photocopy; restricted materials pulled (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Daybook (career moves)1985 May 30 - 1992 Oct. 24, Creator's Id No. 17 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Bardo1986 Jan. 1 - 1986 Dec. 11, Creator's Id No. 18 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - George Shar Slept Here1986 Oct. 1 - 1986 Nov. 21, Creator's Id No. 19 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Trip to India; Itinerary1987 Jan. - Feb., Creator's Id No. 20 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Redoubt1987 Jan. 3 - 1987 May 7, Creator's Id No. 21; Photocopy; restricted materials pulled (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Redoubt1987 May 7 - 1988 Apr. 1, Creator's Id No. 22 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Love Queen of the Amazon1987 July 1 - 1990 June 1, Creator's Id No. 23 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Love Queen; Geo. Shar; Redoubt1987 Nov. 21 - 1990, Creator's Id No. 24 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Johanna 1988 July 7 - 1988 Sept. 24, Creator's Id No. 25 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Bardo; Passage1988 Dec. 12 - 1989 Oct. 31, Creator's Id No. 26 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - New York trip1989 Feb. 28 - 1989 Mar. 18, Creator's Id No. 27 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Letters (Myrna); Bruno II; Shotwell1991 Jan. 21 - 1992 Mar. 13, Creator's Id No. 28 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Trip to Italy1991 May 18, Creator's Id No. 29 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Trip to London; Gulf War1991 - 1992, Creator's Id No. 30 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Point Me to the Home of Light (Desert Storm Redux)1992, Creator's Id No. 31 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Alcinor; Point Me to the Home of Light; Fishlight1992 July 28 - [?], Creator's Id No. 32 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Miami Book Fair; Fishlight; Kosovo War1992 Nov. 22 - 1999 May 29, Creator's Id No. 33 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Rupazampana; Bardo; Mustafa; Kosovo Bombing1993 May 22 - 1999 June 2, Creator's Id No. 34; Photocopy; restricted materials pulled (Box 47, Folder 6, 7)
  - Touching Henru; Redoubt (freeing)1995 Oct. - 1999 Jan. 14, Creator's Id No. 35; Photocopy; restricted materials pulled (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Poetry workshop (with Glover Davis (desc: Phillip Larkin))/ Notes1995, Creator's Id No. 36 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Redoubt research; J.J. Poems1996 Mar. 28 - 1998 Apr. 13, Creator's Id No. 37; Photocopy; restricted materials pulled (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - New Criticism (Ornatowski's lectures)1996, Creator's Id No. 38 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Fishlight; Bardo1997 Aug. - 1998 Mar. 16, Creator's Id No. 39; Photocopy; restricted materials pulled (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Kosovo War; Stanford acquisition [arrival pending]1999 June 27 -, Creator's Id No. 40 (Box 48)
- Series 5. Reviews
  - Published dance & theater reviews: originals and reprints, Creator's Id No. 15.14 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Unpublished reviews, Creator's Id No. 15.15 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Published book reviews: originals, notes, & reprints, Creator's Id No. 15.16 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - San Jose Mercury: review of Christine / Annette, Creator's Id No. 15.17 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - San Francisco Review of Books: Valenzuela and Doubiago reviews, Creator's Id No. 15.18 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Contract for Reviewing Jobs, correspondence, Creator's Id No. 15.19 (Box 49, Folder 6)
- Series 6. Audiovisual materials
  - Subseries 1. Ruth Brinker biography interviews
    - Cecile Pineda interviewing Ruth Brinker[1994?], Creator's Id No. 15.06; 1 sound cassette: analog (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Fourth interview, Planning Fresh start[1994] July 5, Creator's Id No. 15.07; 1 sound cassette: analog (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Ruth Brinker on Bush St., 1994 July 13, Creator's Id No. 15.08; 1 sound cassette: analog (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Ruth Brinker 25-50,1994 July 26, Creator's Id No. 15.09; 1 sound cassette: analog (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Ruth Brinker meeting with San Francisco Board of Education, Creator's Id No. 15.1; 1 sound cassette: analog (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Jeanne Alexander, friend and board member, 1994 July 15, Creator's Id No. 15.11; 1 sound cassette: analog (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Bob Baldoch, KPFA, interviews Ruth Brinker, Creator's Id No. 15.12; 1 sound cassette: analog (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Glen LaMontagne (Fresh Start gardener)1994 July 28, Creator's Id No. 15.13; 1 sound cassette: analog (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 2. Theatre of Man performance tapes
    - Murder in the Cathedral at St. Aidan's Church, San Francisco, Calif., 1970 Jan., Creator's Id No. 15.01; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in., 1/4 in. tape. (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Serpent1971 Apr. 24, Creator's Id No. 15.02; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in., 1/4 in. tape. (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - After Eurydice1973 Feb. 24, Creator's Id No. 15.03; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in., 1/4 in. tape. (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Stoneground at Firehouse Theater (now Lumiere)1974, Creator's Id No. 15.04; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in., 1/4 in. tape. (Box 51, Folder 4)